# Ladislav Vrbsky

MSc in AI, all out for Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Data since 2019. Executes Machine Learning (ML) projects from analyses and prototypes to production and is developing a data platform, all on cloud, leveraging Python and SQL. Interacts with stakeholders and devs and trains others. Is curious, honest, multi-cultural, ambitious and passionate for AI/ML, Data, Cloud and Leadership.

■ ladislav.vrbsky@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/vrbsky

**O** github.com/vrbsky

 $\bigcirc$  +55 (91) 99388-7307

www.vrbsky.com

**♀** Belem, PA, Brazil

#### EXPERIENCE

## • Data Scientist at Vibe & [AWS, Azure, Python, SQL]

Jan 2019 - Present | BRA

- Developed and was responsible for a supervised ML project with a data architecture and MLOps, using AWS, from prototypes to production
- o Proactively co-created and structured an in-house Data Analytics team, its offering and content
- Held numerous meetings with stakeholders, delivering, discussing and pitching data projects
- o Promoted company's data-driven culture by sharing knowledge, besides teaching English
- o Controlled COVID-19 by collecting API data using Azure Functions and visualizing them with Power BI
- o Delivered data PoCs leveraging the AWS and Azure clouds
- o Improved company's management by delivering Business Intelligence (BI) reports in Power BI
- o Avoided client's significant expenses and drove important business decisions by analyzing customer data

# • Cloud Data Engineer & Architect at Órbita & [GCP, Python, SQL]

Apr 2020 - Present | BRA

- o Architected, structured and documented an automated data project on Google Cloud Platform (GCP)
- Collected public data from the web by creating a serverless ETL pipeline
- o Managed remote developers and specified a sub-project of another data collection
- o Delivered data views for business analysts by transforming data with Python and SQL
- o Created a flexible visualiser of tabular data using Python
- Managed the product's GCP account
- Web Developer at Vibe 🗷 [Java, C#, SQL, REST]

Oct 2017 – Jan 2019 | BRA

- o Developed, fixed, improved web apps and services (mostly back-end) for Banpara bank
- Boosted 3x tech support speed by improving automation tool (for 1 frequent issue)
- Applied AI Researcher at UFPA 🗷 [Matlab]

Jan 2016 – Apr 2018 | BRA

- $\circ$  Compared clustering algorithms and respective configs w.r.t. communication delay  $\to$  MSc thesis  $\square$
- Implemented a clustering-based topology optimizer for Smart Grid networks; Open-Sourced
- Junior Software Developer at AgentFly 🗷 [Java]

Apr 2013 – Aug 2014 | CZE

- o Implemented UAV (a.k.a drone) collision avoidance protocol for Air traffic management simulation
- Analyzed and optimized route generation heuristic by extrapolating the collision-based utility values

#### PROJECTS & PUBLICATIONS

- ICNSC 2017 🗷 (Intl. Conference): Clustering techniques for data network planning in Smart Grids 🗷
- Fraud Detection in Energy Grid: Neural Networks, Decision Trees, Fuzzy Logic, Genetic Algorithms
- Memetic algorithm for Traveling Salesman Problem: Genetic Algorithm with local search
- Other ML: Transfer learning (TensorFlow), Simple client-side ML (TensorFlow.js), Color quantization (Matlab)

## SKILLS

- Languages, Libs, Tools: Python, SQL, sklearn, pandas, git, Java, C#, Matlab | Eng, Por, Cze, (Ger)
- Competencies: ML, Statistics, Cloud data tools & archit. (AWS, GCP, Azure), Public speaking, Teaching, BI dev
- Interests: Leadership, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Spark, Kafka, Reinforcement Learning

# EDUCATION

- Federal University of Pará (UFPA) & MSc Applied Computing: Artificial Intelligence Belem, PA, BRA
- Kansas State University (KSU) & MSc period Comp. Science (intl. exchange) Manhattan, KS, USA
- Czech Technical University (CTU) Z BSc Computer and Informatic Science

Prague, CZE

• Extra: Azure ML Scholarship (Udacity), Data Science (AWS, Udemy), Data Engineering (Coursera, Qwiklabs)